James Lee

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Western St, Coffeen, IL 62017, USA

□+1 (850) 252-8258 | **□** jamesdev0505@gmail.com | **□** rot0505

"Impossible is nothing"

Summary _____

As a software developer with 7 years of experience, have been collaborating with a variety of companies including small startups and big communities, which has made me intimately familiar with all the stages of the web lifecycle from the initial architecture to final deployment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. In the past 3 years, I have worked on several cryptocurrency projects such as DeFi, NFT Marketplace piling up great knowledge on blockchain tech. I am also not new to the remote jobs, so I am extremely flexible with my working hours.

Education

University of London

Bachelor of Science (Honours) in Computer Science

2012 - 2015

- Awarded by the University of London, UK and Developed by the member Institution, Goldsmiths, University of London, UK.
- The UOL programmes offered at SIM are long established since 1986.
- A degree from the UOL is a mark of excellence, recognised internationally by employers worldwide.

Skills_____

Languages	${\sf JavaScript}, {\sf ECMAScript} ({\sf ES6\cdot 12}), {\sf TypeScript}, {\sf HTML}, {\sf CSS}, {\sf SCSS/SASS}, {\sf GraphQL}$
Blockchain	Blockchain, Ethers.js, Web3.js, CosmJs, Solidity, Ethereum, Solana, Rust, Cosmos, EVMOS, Blockchain APIs, Moralis, Alchemy
Frameworks	Redux, React Native, Angular, AngularJS, Vue, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Styled Component, Node.js
Libraries/APIs	React, Three.js, D3.js, Phaser, jQuery, Google Maps, Google API
Paradigms	Functional Programming, Object-oriented Design, Promise, Unit Testing
Platforms	AWS(Lambda, EC2, S3, SES, DynamoDB, Lightsail,), Google Cloud Platform(GCP), Heroku, Vercel
Database/Storage	MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Amazon S3, Google Cloud Storage, IPFS
Tools	Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, Jira, Slack, Docker, Webpack, Chrome Developer Tools
Other	Frontend Development, Blockchain Development, Front-end, Web Development, Responsive Design, WebSockets, User Experience(UX), Software Development, HTTP, Ajax

Experience

PageDAO

Web3 Frontend Developer

Jun. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Handled the Web3 integration for different wallet connections and contract integration for multi-chain support, including Ethereum, Polygon, EVMOS.
- Worked with a client to build an open source for GitHub public repository, which everyone can fork to build their own dapp.
- Worked closely with smart contract team to develop and build new dapps. Also work with other teams to integrate with internal protocols into our system.
- Built a front-end application for NFT minting dapp and dao's Membership dapp using React, Redux, TypeScript and Web3.js.
- Improved the front-end architecture and code to make it more modular and reusable.

Technologies: Blockchain, EVM, Polygon, EVMOS, React, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux-Thunk, React Context, TypeScript, Web3.js, Ethers.js, Web3modal, ERC20, ERC721, ECR1155, IPFS, SCSS, Styled Components, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Alchemy, Jest

Plasbit

Frontend Developer

Dec. 2020 - Apr. 2022

- Collaborated with client and other engineers for the project of planning, architecture, development, test and deployment.
- Implemented features and user interfaces to optimize performance of user-facing products and mentored junior front-end developers.
- Handled the pixel-perfect implementation of the specs with React and transformed the app to be mobile-first and fully responsive, then integrated it into Meteor.
- Implemented dynamic and interactive charts in order to evaluate and pivot crypto market data with Recharts and Highcharts and also created animations using CSS and JavaScript.
- Implemented a React compelling front-end banking dashboard panel for complex data visualization with user-friendly search features.
- Used Chrome DevTools to investigate and fix front-end rendering performance issues and computationally intensive bottlenecks.
- Led efforts to research, design, develop, and test blockchain technologies to enable platform features.

Technologies: Web Development, React, React Native, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Meteor, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Material UI(MUI), Ant Design, Node.js, MongoDB, Responsive Web Design, Docker, Bitbucket, Jira, AWS EC2, AWS S3, Firebase, Blockchain APIs

Crosmonauts

Blockchain Developer

Mar. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Built core product features from start to finish; from conception and research to implementation and iteration, all the way through deployment, maintenance, and future iterations.
- Developed a P2E game(Crosmoshooter) using Phaser targeting Cronos Blockchain.
- Integrated blockchain smart contracts in the P2E game to enable \$CROSMO players can be earned while playing the game.
- Interacted with a UX designer to help implement user-facing avatar, item, and land customization tools.
- Structured the database to optimize all the data in a real-time database using MongoDB on AWS EC2.
- Helped create performant backend systems by implementing reusable components, libraries, and design systems as applicable.
- Worked as a dev-ops engineer to deploy game and backend services in production with AWS EC2.

Technologies: WebGL, Blockchain, P2E Game, Cronos, React, React Native, Redux Toolkit, TypeScript, Phaser, Colyseus, Multiplayer, Web3.js, Ethers.js, ERC721, Styled Components, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS EC2, Jest, Material UI(MUI)

Polysport

WebGL Frontend Developer

Aug. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- Developed and maintained rendering engine features, tools, and related systems.
- Created virtual tour website using Three.js and React Three Fiber.
- Optimized 3D glb models using gltf pipeline to improved the site speed.
- Served as technical tie breaker for all technical decisions on the team.

Technologies: WebGL, React, Redux Saga, React Three Fiber, React 3D Viewer, Three.js, Google Model Viewer, GLTF Pipeline, Styled Components, Jest

Gloassboro Rentals

Full Stack Developer

Feb. 2019 - Aug. 2020

- Built a front-end widget that is added as a single external script to an HTML page but works as a big library using vanilla JavaScript and jQuery.
- Optimized the front-end portion to make a fully functional and performance website using Webpack and many other compressing tools like JPEGmini.
- Wrote many new web apps, designed APIs and manipulated big data and converted a traditional web application to a single-page application using AJAX and a state management layer in JavaScript and Java.
- Gained experience with various web development tools, including Git, Cloud Services like AWS, Azure, GCP, Heroku and so on.
- Supported the launch and growth of the developer community through various initiatives including public engagement and publishing blog posts and whitepapers.

Technologies: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Google APIs, Google Map, MySQL, JPEGmini, Ajax,

Git, Github, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Heroku, Netlify, Vercel

Fullstack Developer May. 2016 - Nov. 2018

• Managed the product from idea to launch of web apps and solved a payment integration problem that required high accuracy for different user banks.

- Redesigned and rebuilt over 10 companies' websites and resulted in remarkable growth for over 5 startup companies.
- Developed custom websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and and provided API endpoints with Laravel/CI/PHP and MySQL.
- Wrote a framework to generate new custom websites with custom database back-end for improved roll out and prototyping.
- Analysed and communicated complex technical requirement.

Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, RESTful APIs, MySQL, Figma, PhotoShop, Slack, Objected-oritented Programming(OOP)